{
  "id": "14216f52-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
  "name": "Climbing, Lifting, Rigging and Hoisting",
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": "14218fe6-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "14218fe6-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "What is the maximum weight a worker is permitted to manually lift on the job according to Alberta laws?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": ["25 lbs", "25 kgs", "70 lbs", "There is no specific law regarding the maximum weight a worker can lift."],
      "correctAnswer": ["There is no specific law regarding the maximum weight a worker can lift."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "1421a1c0-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "1421a1c0-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "Which term describes lifting an object that is too far away from your abdomen increasing the risk of injury?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": ["Underextension", "Overextension", "Hyperextension", "Flexion"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Overextension"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "1421bdcc-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "1421bdcc-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "When performing a manual lift, putting the object down involves the same technique as lifting the load, only in the reverse order.",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correctAnswer": ["True"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "1421c3d0-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "1421c3d0-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "What is the safety factor for general rigging and hoisting operations?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": ["20:1", "10:1", "5:1", "2:1"],
      "correctAnswer": ["5:1"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "1421c79a-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "1421c79a-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "All the following are recognized synthetic fibre web sling configurations except",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": ["Triangle and choker fitting", "Reverse endless return fitting", "Return eye sling", "Endless or grommet sling"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Reverse endless return fitting"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "1421f1ca-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "1421f1ca-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "What are the two most common materials used to manufacture wire rope slings?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": ["Nylon and polyester", "Tungsten and titanium", "Cadmium and nickel", "Carbon steel and stainless steel"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Carbon steel and stainless steel"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "1422048a-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "1422048a-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "Which type of triangle is formed when using the recommended safe lifting angle for sling legs?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": ["Equilateral", "Isosceles", "Right", "Scalene"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Equilateral"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "142209b2-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "142209b2-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "Select the most commonly used shackle.",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": ["Safety type chain shackle", "Round pin chain shackle", "Screw pin anchor shackle", "Round pin anchor shackle"],
      "correctAnswer": ["Screw pin anchor shackle"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "1422125e-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "1422125e-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "Select the device often used to support long loads that are difficult to handle while being hoisted?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": ["A swivel", "A spreader bar", "An eyebolt", "A snatch block"],
      "correctAnswer": ["A spreader bar"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "14221754-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "14221754-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "Which sling configuration is rated for the least lifting capacity?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Single vertical hitch",
        "Basket hitch",
        "Choker hitch",
        "These configurations all have the same lifting capacity."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Choker hitch"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "142219c0-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "142219c0-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "Which sling configuration is the safest choice for moving a loose bundle of pipe while providing the greatest lifting capacity?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Single basket hitch",
        "Single choker hitch",
        "Double choker hitch",
        "Double wrap basket hitch"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Double wrap basket hitch"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "14221b6e-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "14221b6e-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "Which motion is used to signal an 'emergency stop' to the crane operator?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Both arms are swept out from the body at shoulder height.",
        "Closed fist with thumb up.",
        "Point the forefinger down and rotate hand.",
        "Make fists with outstretched thumbs and motion thumbs towards each other."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Both arms are swept out from the body at shoulder height."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "14221e16-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "14221e16-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "At what height must an employer have a guardrail erected for a temporary work area?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "2.4 m (8 ft)",
        "3.0 m (10 ft)",
        "3.7 m (12 ft)",
        "4.2 m (14 ft)"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["3.0 m (10 ft)"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "1422203c-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "1422203c-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "Which scaffold system component is designed to prevent objects such as tools and materials from falling?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Toeboard",
        "Brace",
        "Mud sill",
        "Transom"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Toeboard"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "14222564-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "14222564-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "Your full body harness was accidentally soaked with a corrosive chemical. What should you do?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Switch it with a co-worker’s harness.",
        "Give it to your apprentice and buy a new one.",
        "Destroy it or return it to the manufacturer.",
        "Wash and dry it."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Destroy it or return it to the manufacturer."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "14222802-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "14222802-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "What standard must a full body harness meet if manufactured on or after July 1, 2009?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "WCB",
        "ULC",
        "PPE",
        "CSA"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["CSA"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "14222974-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "14222974-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "How often must you inspect your fall arrest equipment?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Before use on the first shift of the week.",
        "Before use on the first shift of the month.",
        "Before use on each shift.",
        "Only after the equipment has been used to protect you from a fall."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Before use on each shift."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "14222adc-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "14222adc-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "What is the minimum distance a ladder must protrude above the intended landing point?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "0.3 m (1 ft)",
        "1 m (3 ft)",
        "¼ the length of the ladder",
        "¼ the distance of the base of the ladder from the base of the wall or structure"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["1 m (3 ft)"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "14222c44-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "14222c44-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "The safety factor for a scaffold must be designed and constructed to support at least how many times the load that may be imposed on it?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Three times",
        "Four times",
        "Five times",
        "Six times"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Five times"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "14222d84-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "14222d84-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "When conducting a hazard assessment related to lifting and handling a load, your employer must consider which of the following?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Weight, size, and shape of the load",
        "Cost of renting moving equipment",
        "Insured value of the load to be moved",
        "Number of people required to move the load"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Weight, size, and shape of the load"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "14222ec4-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "14222ec4-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "What is not an example of a recommended lifting technique?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Avoid awkward postures",
        "Lift loads smoothly",
        "Lift no higher than eye level",
        "Begin lifting at knee level"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Lift no higher than eye level"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "14223054-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "14223054-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "What is the goal of proper lifting technique?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "To constantly practice lifting to become more skilled.",
        "To increase lifting efficiency and capacity with practice.",
        "To increase the number of lifts performed per day.",
        "To eliminate loading stresses on the soft tissue of your lower back."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["To eliminate loading stresses on the soft tissue of your lower back."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "142231bc-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "142231bc-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "How is working load limit (WLL) defined?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Breaking strength divided by the safety factor",
        "Safety factor divided by the breaking strength",
        "The ultimate tensile strength (UTS)",
        "The safest way to move and lower a load"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Breaking strength divided by the safety factor"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "14223306-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "14223306-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "What does the term shock loading mean when applied to rigging equipment?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "A stray spark from a work operation occurs when the sling has load applied to it.",
        "The sling is exposed to stress by having the load suddenly started or stopped.",
        "The sling comes into contact with an electrical conductor when the sling is loaded.",
        "The sling is used as an electrical conductor to connect to a load sensor in the lifting equipment."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["The sling is exposed to stress by having the load suddenly started or stopped."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "1422345a-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "1422345a-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "What rigging factor of safety is to be used when lifting and transporting workers?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "2:1",
        "5:1",
        "10:1",
        "20:1"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["10:1"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "1422359a-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "1422359a-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "How often must rigging be inspected?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "When first put into service and every three months after that",
        "At the beginning of each work shift",
        "At the beginning of the first shift of the month",
        "At the beginning of the first shift of the week"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["At the beginning of each work shift"],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "142236da-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "topicId": "142236da-4208-11ef-ad1e-12cb12165fd3",
      "question": "What is the recommended sling angle when rigging a load?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Never greater than 45°",
        "Never less than 45°",
        "Never greater than 60°",
        "Never less than 60°"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Never less than 60°"],
      "explanation": ""
    }
  ]
}
